Question everything.
Heretic is a thriller, horror film directed by Scott Beck.
Two young missionaries are forced to prove their faith when they knock
on the wrong door and are greeted by a diabolical Mr.
Reed, becoming ensnared in his deadly game of cat-and-mouse.
Mr. Reed, played by Hugh Grant.
Sister Barnes, played by Sophie Thatcher.
Sister Paxton, played by Chloe East.
Elder Kennedy, played by Topher Grace.
Prophet, played by Elle Young.
Pedestrian, played by Julie Lynn-Mortensen.
Heretic is a 2024 American psychological horror film written
and directed by Scott Beck and Bryan Woods.
It follows two young Mormon missionaries (Sophie Thatcher and Chloe East) who visit the home of an eccentric man (Hugh Grant) after he expresses
interest in the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints (LDS Church), only for his true intentions to quickly become clear.
Heretic premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 8,
2024, and was released in the United States by A24 on November 8.
It received positive reviews and grossed over $59
million worldwide on a budget of $10 million.
Grant received Best Actor nominations at the Golden Globes, the Critics' Choice Awards, and the BAFTA Awards,
while Beck and Woods received an Independent Spirit Awards nomination for Best Screenplay.
The film explores themes of faith, control, sociopath, religion, cat and mouse.
The tone is dark and intense.